

ANJUM ALI

Nationality: Pakistani (+92) 3013232084 **Date of birth:** 18/10/1993

Gender: Male **Email address:** anjum.ali@riphahfsd.edu.pk

WeChat: anjumali2233

Address: Chack Peroana Shumali P/O Jabboana Tehsil 18-Hazari, 38000 Jhang (Pakistan)

ABOUT ME

Passionate & compassionate with my task to energize innovative institutions. I am a software engineering graduate, having 18 years' education with a Master's degree, and an interest in quality research work. I am currently looking for a scholarship opportunity from a top-ranked university y for doing a Ph.D. to polish my research and analytical skills in my field. Indeed, having entered this digital epoch, I am more than greedy for something new.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Masters of Science (MS) in Software Engineering

University of Agriculture Faisalabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan [2019 –2022]

Field(s) of study: Software Engineering

Thesis: Boll Rot Disease Detection in Cotton Using Deep Learning

Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Computer Science

University of Agriculture Faisalabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan [2013 –2015]

Field(s) of study: Computer Science

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Computer Science

University of Punjab Lahore, Lahore, Pakistan [2011 –2013]

Field(s) of study: Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics

PUBLICATIONS

Anjum Ali, Muhammad Azam Zia, Muhammad Ahsan Latif, Sukana Zulfqar, & Muhammad Asim. (2023). A
COMPARATIVE STUDY OF DEEP LEARNING TECHNIQUES FOR BOLL ROT DISEASE DETECTION IN
COTTON CROPS. Agricultural Sciences Journal, 5(1), 58–71. https://doi.org/10.56520/asj.v5i1.253

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lecturer (Software Engineering)

Riphah International University, Faisalabad, Pakistan [25/10/2022 - Current]

Lecturer (Computer Science)

Madina Group of Colleges, Faisalabad, Pakistan [15/08/2017 - 25/07/2021]

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming language PYTHON / C, C++, / Software LaTeX / Microsoft Office (Microsoft) / Spyder/Jupyter/Anaconda / Database: Oracle, MYSQL, SQL +, Access. / Microsoft SQL and Oracle SQL / End Note / Python (NumPy, Pandas, Keras, Sci-Kit Learn, TensorFlow)

CERTIFICATION

Artificial Intelligence with Python -PIAIC

CCNA (Routing and Switching)- CORVIT

MANAGEMENT DUTIES

Member of Audit and NCEAC Preparation Committee at Riphah International University, Pakistan

REFERENCES

Dr. Muhammad Ahsan Latif

Associate Professor

University of Agriculture Faisalabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan

mahsanlatif@uaf.edu.pk

Dr. Imran Mumtaz

Assistant Professor

University of Agriculture Faisalabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan

imranmumtaz@uaf.edu.pk